月光男孩
字幕由SSK字幕組傾情譯制
字幕僅供學習，勿用於商
轉載請註明出處，版權歸片方所有
新浪微博@SSK字幕組
官網：www.sskzmz.com
月光男孩
翻譯 Dark Paradise
翻譯 林白一
翻譯 JUNO
翻譯 yuli
校對 Luke
特效 BUNNY
壓制 fsffsfs
總監 Luke
第一部分 小不點
第二部分 奇倫
第三部分 小黑
嘿 夥計
Hey, my man, t., what's going on dawg?
-你好 -你好
- What's up, what's up. - How you doing?
-你需要什麼 -你能幫幫我嗎 夥計
- What you need? - Can you help me out, man?
不 兄弟 我幫不了你
- No, I can't do it, bro. You gotta keep moving. I can't do it.
-求你了 夥計 -我幫不了你
- Come on, man. - Keep it movin'.
-孩子 -讓一下 夥計
- Boy. - Step aside, man.
-你好啊 -你怎麼樣
How you doing? - What's good with you?
我很好 夥計 還是像往常一樣在這兒忙活著
I'm all right, man. I'm out here handling business as usual.
聽著 夥計 我沒有不尊重你的意思
Look, man, I don't mean no disrespect or nothing to you,
我只是問問能不能給我點
I'm just trying to see if I can get a little--
給不了你 夥計 你知道現在幾點嗎
you can't get nothing, man. You know what time it is, bruh?
我一直幫你盯著警察
I keep looking out for you, man.
就一丁點 行嗎
Just a little something, man?
一丁點你也得花錢買啊
All my something cost a little something, man.
沒錢就趕緊走人吧大兄弟
If he ain't got it get to stepping, nigga.
你知道現在幾點了嗎 我不想老是自說自話
You know what time it is? I don't feel like repeating myself.
嘿 你知道我的夥計對嗎 胡安
Hey, you know you my man, right Juan?
這個兄弟
This nigga...
你傻了麼 夥計
Yo. Trippin', man.
看你能不能為我做點事
See-see-see-see if you can do something here for me...
媽的我剛剛怎麼跟你說的 東西給我
What the fuck I just told you? Let me get this shit!
給我滾開
Nigga, get the fuck out of here, man.
滾
Go on!
噢 看著那個人 夥計
Oh, get that nigga, man.
-你怎麼樣 -我很好 很好
- What's up? - I'm good, good.
-我就在這 你知道的 -是的
- I'm just out here, you know. - Yeah.
平常的一天
Regular day.
這裏很隱蔽 你需要錢我就找人拿錢
It's in the cut. Everybody cleaned out if you need anything.
-生意還好嗎 -是的 還好
- Business good? - Yeah it's good.
-我給你帶了點 -不 你先保管好
I got something for you-- - no, no. Hold onto that.
週末整理好給我
Empty the register on the weekend.
好的 沒問題
All right, no problem, son.
你媽現在怎麼樣了
How's your mom feeling now?
噢 她挺好 她很好
Oh, she doing good. She doing excellent.
-好多了 -好多了
- Better? - She doing better.
你知道的
You know.
我一直在為她祈禱 夥計
She's in my prayers, man.
非常感謝
Most naturally. Thank you.
謝謝你給我的機會 我會努力的
Thanks for the opportunity. I'm out here.
-抓住他 -你過來
- Get him! - Get your ass right here.
-抓住他 -你為什麼總跑
- Get him! - Why you always runnin'?
別跑啊死基佬
Goin' around with that faggot ass, bro!
-還能不能抓住他了 -揍他
- Ain't gonna catch him! - Kick his ass!
-那就追啊 夥計 -抓住他
- Run, then, nigga! - Get his gay ass!
-來啊 兄弟 -抓住他
- Come on, bro! - Catch that nigga!
去後面
Go around the back.
小傢伙 你在這幹嘛呢
What you doin' in here, li'l man?
嗯哼
Huh?
你不和陌生人說話嗎
You don't talk to strangers?
好吧 沒事了
A'ight. It's cool.
沒事了
We cool.
聽著
Listen...
我要去弄點吃的
I'm about to go get something to eat.
要不要和我一起去
You're welcome to join me if you want.
我可以從前門走嗎
It's okay if I take the front door?
嗯哼
Hmm?
來吧
Come on now.
外面很好
Can't be no worse out here.
你不打算告訴我你的名字了嗎
You not gonna tell me what yo' name is?
那你住在哪呢
How 'bout where you live?
我得把你送回去 小傢伙
I got to get you home, little man.
不能讓你在毒窩裏亂跑
Can't have you just runnin' around these dope holes.
你明白嗎
You understand?
嘿 我的錯
Hey, hey, hey, my bad.
噢 小伙子 你知道我不會這麼對你的
Oh man, you know I ain't gonna do you like that.
我道歉 好嗎
Hey man, I apologize, all right?
我只是想讓你說句話
I'm just trying to get you to say something.
嘿
Hey...
我道歉
I apologize.
好了
All right.
你現在這樣好了
You all right now...
但我女朋友會過來找你
...until my girl come get you, though.
她會讓你說話的
She gonna make you talk.
我一會回來
Be right back.
-特瑞莎 -嘿 寶貝
Teresa! - Hey, baby.
我在毒窩發現了這個小男孩
I found this little boy in a dope spot.
在哪裏發現的
- Found a little boy in a what?
那裏沒人吸毒
Wasn't no crack heads up in there.
他自己在那兒
He by himself.
但是他不願意說話 你能不能
He ain't talking though, so why don't you see
讓他說幾句話
if you can get him to say something.
-真的 -去跟他說幾句
- Really? - Just go talk to him.
去吧
Just go talk to him.
真是難以置信
I cannot believe you.
-我愛你 -是誰能讓你這麼做
- Love you. - Who would you do something like this?
你不說話但你可挺能吃
You don't talk much but you damn sure can eat.
沒關係 寶貝
That's all right, baby.
等你吃好喝好了再說話也不遲
You ain't got to talk 'til you get good and ready.
我叫奇倫
My name is chiron.
大家都叫我小不點
People call me little.
好的 小不點
All right then, little.
那我就叫你的名字了
Well im'ma call you by your name, then.
你住在哪兒 奇倫
Where you from, chiron?
自由城[邁阿密的一個街區]
Liberty city.
你和媽媽一起生活
You live with your mama?
是的
Yes.
你爸爸呢
What about your daddy?
沒事
That's all right.
你想讓我們把你帶回家嗎
You want us to take you home, then,
在你吃完飯之後
after you get finished eating your food?
你得告訴我們你住在哪兒 孩子
Yeah, you gotta tell us where you live, bruh.
不
No...
好吧
Okay.
你今晚可以留在這裏
You can stay here tonight.
特瑞莎
Teresa...
你想這樣嗎
Would you like that?
好
Okay.
怎麼回事
What happened?
怎麼了 奇倫
What happened, chiron?
你昨晚怎麼沒回家呢
Why you didn't come home like you supposed to?
你是誰
And who is you?
無名氏
Nobody.
我昨天看見他的
I found him yesterday.
在十五號街的一個窩點
Found him in a hole on 15th.
是的 那一間
Yeah. That one.
幾個男孩對他窮追不捨
Some boys chased him in the cut.
他嚇壞了
He's scared more than anything.
直到今天早上他才告訴我住哪
He wouldn't tell me where he lived 'til this morning.
好吧 謝謝你照顧他
Well, thanks for seeing to him.
通常他能自己照顧自己
He usually can take care of hisself...
他是可以 可是
...he good that way, but...
小傢伙
Little man.
你是我的寶貝 奇倫 你知道嗎
You a real damn prize, chiron, you know that?
該回家的時候就要回家
You got'sta come home when you meant to come home.
聽到了嗎
You hear?
沒事了 寶貝
That's all right, baby.
沒事了
That's all right.
媽媽很開心你回來了
Mama just glad you're home.
不
Nuh-uh.
你不能看電視
TV privilege is revoked.
找點書看看
Find something for you to read.
球在哪
Where the ball at?
我得不到球
I don't got the ball no more!
嘿 小不點
Hey, little!
你好啊
Wassup, man?
嘿 凱文
Hey, Kevin.
你為什麼要走
Why'd you leave?
我不知道
I don't know.
是的 玩一會就無聊了
Yeah, it get borin' after a while.
怎麼了
What?
流血了嗎
Is it bleedin'?
怎麼了
What?
你很有趣 夥計
You funny, man.
你為什麼這麼說
Why you say that?
你就是有趣
You just is, that's all.
你為什麼老是被欺負 夥計
Why do you always let people pick on you, man?
你什麼意思
What you mean?
你老是讓他們欺負你
You always letting them pick on you.
那我該怎麼辦
So what I gotta do?
你應該
All you gotta do
向他們展示你並不軟弱
is show these niggas you ain't soft.
但我不軟弱
But I ain't soft.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
但如果他們不知道就毫無意義
But it don't mean nothing if they don't know it.
來吧
Come on.
你想讓那些傻瓜整天欺負你嗎
You want these fools to pick on you every day?
看到了嗎 小不點
See little?
我知道你不軟弱
I knew you wasn't soft.
來吧 夥計
Come on, man.
把頭伸過來
Give me your head.
頭靠在我手上
Let your head rest in my hand.
放鬆
Relax.
我抓著你 我保證
I got you. I promise.
我不會放手的
I'm not going to let you go.
嘿 夥計 我抓著你
Hey man, I got you.
就是這樣
There you go.
十秒鐘
Ten seconds.
感受到了嗎
Feel that right there?
你處在世界中心 夥計
You're in the middle of the world, man.
做得好
That's good.
就像這樣
Do like this.
看看你
Look at you.
再敏捷一點
More athletic.
就這樣
There you go.
是的 我認為你準備好了
Yeah. I think you ready.
我認為你會游泳了
I think we got a swimmer.
你想試試嗎 你準備好了嗎
You wanna try? You ready to swim?
來吧
Go.
好樣的 夥計
Yeah, man!
好樣的
Yeah!
我跟你說 夥計
Let me tell you something, man.
黑人無處不在
There are black people everywhere.
記住這一點 好嗎
You remember that, okay?
這個世界上
No place you can go in the world
到處都有黑人的蹤影
ain't got no black people.
我們是這個星球上最早誕生的人類
We was the first ones on this planet.
我來這裏很久了
I been here a long time...
但我來自古巴
...but I'm from Cuba.
古巴有很多黑人
Lotta black folks in Cuba,
但你在這裏不知道這些
but you wouldn't know it from being here, though.
我當時也是個虎頭虎腦的小個子 夥計
I was a wild li'l shorty, man.
像你一樣
Just like you.
在月光下光著腳奔跑
Runnin' around with no shoes on when the moon was out.
有一次
This one time...
我路過一位奶奶
I run by this old... This old lady.
我在跑 一直跑
I was runnin', hollerin'...
像一個傻孩子
...and cuttin' a fool, boy.
老奶奶截下我
This old lady, she stopped me.
她說
She said...
奔跑
..."running around...
追逐光亮的方向
...catching up all that light.
在月光下
In moonlight...
黑人男孩是藍色的
...black boys look blue.
你是藍色的
You blue.
所以我以後就叫你
That's what I gon' call you.
藍
Blue."
那你的名字叫藍嗎
So your name blue?
不
Nah.
有些時候你得自己決定你要做什麼
At some point you gotta decide for yourself who you gonna be.
沒人能替你做決定
Can't let nobody make that decision for you.
你喜歡游泳嗎 夥計
How you like swimming, man?
這麼喜歡啊
That much, huh?
嘿 等下 等下
Hey, hold up, hold up.
選一個
Pick one.
啊
Aah...
哈哈 選得好
Ha ha. Good choice.
把它放你口袋
Put it in your pocket.
嘿
Hey.
等一下 喂
Yo, hold up. Whoa, whoa, hey--
來吧
come on.
你還好嗎 小不點
What's going on, little man?
來吧
Come on!
夥計 他們和我的一樣
Man, they're all the same as mine.
至少我的看起來不像弗萊迪·克魯格
At least mine don't look like Freddy kruger.
你的醜爆了
Yours ugly as hell.
我的一點也不醜
Mine don't look like no peanut.
告訴你 我的一點也不醜
Telling you, mine does not look like no peanut.
誰讓他進來的
Who let his ass in?
有人和你一起嗎
Somebody with you?
夥計 我發誓它鎖上了
Man, I swear it was locked.
夥計 沒犯規 沒犯規
Man, ain't no foul. Ain't no foul.
怎麼了
S'up?!
你死定了 打你的臉
You're dead, baby! Right in your face!
我是花了錢 但這不是我要買的啊
It's what I paid for. It ain't what I bought.
夥計 這已經是高級貨了
Man, that's grade a quality.
你還想要我怎麼樣
What else you want me to do?
夥計 這更像是下等貨
Nigga, this shit look more like grade c.
夥計 這話我可不愛聽
Man, look. I ain't goin' with that, man!
我要把錢要回來
I want my money back.
什麼 不接受退款 夥計
What?! Ain't no refund, man.
收好它 夥計 走吧
Just stuff it, man. Keep movin'. Go on.
你還好嗎
Yo what's up? You all right?
我以為你去度假了呢
Thought you was on vacation or some shit.
拜託 夥計 這裏哪有假期
Come on, man. No vacation out here.
我得工作啊
I know the work, you know that.
去瑞士或別的地方
Going to Switzerland or some shit.
瑞士 夥計
Switzerland, man.
可能會去巴西吧 你知道的 和兩個好看的姑娘
Maybe Brazil, you know, with two bad bitches.
小花生幹得怎麼樣
How peanut working out?
他很好 我能搞定他
Peanut good, man. I got him at in check.
他在他該在的地方 你知道
He's staying in his place, you know.
他們在吸毒嗎
They basin'?
當然不是了 你知道我不會容許這種事情發生
Hell no, you know I ain't gonna let that go down.
你現在都讓人在這裏點火了嗎
Yo, nigga, you lettin' people light up at the spot, now?
-噢 不 -媽的
- Hell no. - The f--
你知道我不會容許這種事情發生
come on, you know I ain't gonna let that happen, man.
媽的
The fuck, man.
夥計 怎麼回事
Yo nigga, what's up?
嘿 嘿 沒什麼 夥計
Hey, hey, it's all good, man.
-你他媽在幹嘛 -沒事 胡安
- The fuck you doing? - It's all good, Juan.
媽的
Fuck.
-一切都好 -滾出來
- It's all good-- - get out the fucking car!
-冷靜點 夥計 -閉嘴
- Calm down, man. - Shut the fuck up.
你有毛病嗎
What's wrong with you?
你以為你是誰
Who the hell you think you is?
給我滾遠點
Bitch, get the fuck out of here.
什麼 所以你要撫養我兒子嗎
What, so you gon' raise my son now?
你要撫養我兒子嗎
You gon' raise my son?
-我想的沒錯 -我不養你養嗎
Yeah... that's what I thought. - You gon' raise him?
你要接著賣給我毒品
You gon' keep sellin' me rocks?
混蛋
Motherfucker.
別給我擺出一副愛理不理的樣子
Don't give me that "You gotta get it from somewhere" Shit, nigga.
我就要從你這裏買
I'm gettin' it from you.
但你還會撫養我兒子 不是嗎
But you gon' raise my son though, right?
你看過他走路的樣子嗎 胡安
You ever see the way he walk, Juan?
你注意你說的話
You watch your damn mouth.
你要告訴他為什麼別的孩子都欺負他嗎
You gon' tell him why the other boys kick his ass all the time?
你要告訴他嗎
You gon' tell him?
你個垃圾
You ain't shit.
走 我們走
Come on! Let's go!
你們瞅啥
The fuck y'all lookin' at?
特瑞莎
Teresa.
你的小男朋友來了
Your boyfriend's here.
孩子
Boy.
今天要跟我說話嗎
You talking to me today?
好吧
Okay.
沒關係
That's alright.
反正我也不想跟你說話
I don't wanna talk to you, anyway.
你知道她喜歡你 是吧
You know she got a crush on you, right?
你還好嗎
You all right?
你一路走過來的嗎
You walk all the way here?
好吧
All right.
首先 重中之重 你不能坐在這個位置
First things first. You can't sit at my table like that.
你不能背對著門坐 起來
You can't sit with your back to the door, come on.
如果有人悄悄靠近你 你會渾然不知
Ain't gonna know if somebody creepin' up on you.
好了 看到了嗎
All right, see that?
現在一切盡收眼底
Now you can see everything.
想什麼呢
What's over there?
我昨晚看見你媽媽了
I saw your mama last night.
我討厭她
I hate her.
嗯
Hmm.
嗯 我猜你也是
Yeah, I bet you do.
我也不喜歡我媽媽
I hated my mom, too.
儘管我現在很想她
I miss her like hell now though.
這就是對這件事我要說的
That's all I'm gon' say about that.
謝謝
Thank you.
什麼是基佬
What's a faggot?
基佬是
A faggot is...
是一個侮辱同性戀的詞
...A word used to make gay people feel bad.
-我是基佬嗎 -不
- Am I a faggot? - No.
不是
No.
你可以是同性戀 但你不能讓別人叫你基佬
You can be gay, but you gotta let nobody call you no faggot.
我是說 除非
I mean, unless...
我怎麼知道我是不是
How do I know?
你會知道的
You just do.
我覺得
I think.
到時候你就知道了
You'll know when you know.
嘿
Hey...
你現在還不會知道 好嗎
You ain't gotta know right now, all right?
現在還不會
Not yet.
你販毒嗎
Do you sell drugs?
嗯
Yeah.
那我媽媽
And my mama...
她是不是吸毒
...she do drugs, right?
嗯
Yeah.
好 脫氧核糖核酸
Okay, deoxyribonucleic acid.
很長的一個詞 對不對
Long word, right?
好 它本質上就是基因
All right, it's basically genes.
我知道你們還不知道這是什麼意思
I know y'all don't know what that means
但是請先認真聽
but just hang with me for a second.
本質上這個長
So it's basically this long--
奇倫 你需要什麼嗎
chiron, you need something?
他忘了換衛生棉
Hey yo, that nigga forgot to change his tampon.
抱歉 皮爾斯老師
I'm sorry, Mr. Pierce.
他今天有女性生理問題
He just having woman problems today.
-對不對 小不點 -好了 特雷爾 夠了
Ain't that right, little? - All right, Terrell, that's enough.
不 小不點可覺得不夠
Nah, can't be enough for little..
你要多少 小不點
How much you need, little?
-不要那樣叫我 -好了 特雷爾 到此為止
- Don't call me that! - All right Terrell, that's it.
你想幹嘛 奇倫 看我削你
Hey, what you gonna do, chiron? I'll fuck you up.
特雷爾 出去
Hey yo, Terrell, out!
拜託 你怎麼了
Come on, man. What's wrong with you?
我們講到哪了
Where were we?
脫氧核糖核酸本質上是一個很長的模型
DNA is basically this long model...
等我收拾你 小不點
Im'ma be waitin' for your ass, little.
別害怕 奇倫
Come on, chiron.
奇倫 怎麼了 兄弟
Chiron, what's up, man?
天吶 你在發什麼呆 哥們
Damn, nigga. You straight spaced, dawg.
學校人都走完了 你不回家嗎
Yo, school been out. You ain't going home?
呃
Uh...
你在這幹嘛
What you doin' here?
留校 兄弟
Detention, man.
埃姆斯逮到我在樓梯間打炮
Aimes caught me with this trick in the stairway.
-真倒霉 -是啊
- Damn. - Yeah.
跟誰
With who?
你還真是個八婆 兄弟
Damn, you nosey, nigga.
-我的錯 -不是 我開玩笑的
- My bad-- - no, I'm playing, yo.
聽著 我只是想快點做完 你知道嗎
Look, I wanted some quick head you know,
但是那個小妞老是說「用力 凱文」
but this chick all like "Hit that shit, Kevin.
「用你的大雞巴操我」
Hit it with that big dick."
這麼誇我有意思麼
Why she got to compliment a nigga for?
所以我就說「好吧 我們來吧」 你知道嗎
So I'm like "A'ight. Shit. We can do this", you know?
然後我就開始大力干她
So I started banging her back out, dawg.
我是說大力干她
I'm talking I'm banging her back out.
但是她大吼大叫
She went and made all this fucking noise though.
然後埃姆斯就進來了 弄得跟警察一樣
So aimes come in, acted all five-o and shit,
差點讓我停學 哥們
almost had my ass suspended, dawg.
雖然我供認不諱
I talked it out, though.
但是我告訴他我們是青梅竹馬 類似的話
I told him we was like childhood sweethearts and all of that,
所以我只被留校 還不錯
so I just got detention, it's cool.
-不錯 -這件事只有我們兩個人知道 對吧
- Cool. - That stay between us, a'ight?
對
Yeah.
我知道你會守口如瓶的 兄弟
I know you can keep a secret, dawg.
真心話 好了 我要走了
Real talk though, I gotta go, a'ight,
在那個傻逼改變注意之前
before this fool change his mind.
好的 小凱
All right, kev.
回見 小黑
See you, black.
-嘿 媽媽 -你今晚不能待在這兒
- Hey, mama. - Uh-uh. You cannot be here tonight.
我有客人要來
I got company coming.
找個能收留你的地方吧
Find somewhere for you to be.
好了
All right...
我喝水 這杯杜松子酒給你
...water for me... And a little gin for you.
拜託
Boy please.
我知道胡安以前經常給你酒喝
I know Juan used to give you that gin.
但是現在他不在了 小不點
But we ain't doing that up in here, shorty.
你不覺得我的笑話很好笑嗎
You don't think my joke was funny?
怎麼了
What's wrong?
沒事
Nothing.
我沒事
I'm good.
才怪
No.
我知道沒事是什麼樣 你現在一點都不好
I've seen good and you ain't it.
在我家不要再把頭低著了
Stop putting your head down in my house.
你知道我的規矩
You know my rule.
這間房子裏都是愛和驕傲
It's all love and all pride in this house.
懂我的意思嗎
You feel me?
我聽不見你說話
I can't hear you.
懂我的意思嗎
Do you feel me?
懂
Yeah.
-好 -我懂你的意思
- Okay. - I feel you.
好的
All right.
謝謝你收留我
Thank you for this.
孩子 別這樣
Boy, please,
你知道如果需要你隨時都可以待在這兒 好嗎
you know you can stay here any time you need to, okay?
隨時
Any time.
嗯
Yeah.
謝謝你 特瑞莎 真的感謝
Thank you, Teresa. I mean it.
如果你還想待在這兒
Now, if you gon' stay here, though,
你就得學會如何
you gonna have to learn how to make a bed
鋪好床 孩子
better than this, boy.
-什麼 -什麼
- What? - What you mean, "What"?
把那個給我 不是你這樣鋪床的
Give me that. That ain't how you make up no bed.
你肯定覺得自己很狡猾
You think you slick, too.
自己做錯了
You know, do it all wrong
這樣特瑞莎就可以來幫你弄好
so Teresa can come over here and do it right.
我知道你打什麼鬼主意
I know what you doing.
你和胡安
Oof, you and Juan.
你們兩個真不愧是好兄弟
Y'all two, thick as thieves.
那個給我
Give me that.
好了
All right.
還需要我做什麼嗎 親愛的
Do you need anything else from me, sweetheart?
呃 沒了 我很好
Uh, no, I'm good.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 我明天早上叫醒你
All right, I'm gonna wake you up in the morning.
你好嗎 小黑
You good, black?
奇倫
Chiron!
-嘿 寶貝 -嘿 媽媽
- Hey! Hey, baby! - Hey, mama.
你昨晚去哪兒了
Where'd you go last night?
什麼
What?
怎麼了
Why?
我是不是你媽媽
I'm yo' mama, ain't I?
為什麼你不回家 孩子
Why you ain't just come home later, boy?
你讓我一直擔心你
You had me worried about you.
我猜你長大了
I guess you getting grown.
我不能一直把你留在我身邊
I can't be keeping up with you all the time.
寶貝 特瑞莎怎麼樣
Anyway baby, how Teresa doing?
自從葬禮之後 我就沒見過她
I ain't seen her since the funeral.
媽媽把自己鎖在門外了
Listen, mama locked herself out the door, yeah?
你來開下門吧
Can you come let her in?
快點 寶貝
Come on, baby.
讓我進去吧 寶貝
Let me in, baby.
寶貝 求你了
Baby, come on.
我以為你說過
I thought you said--
媽媽 我以為
mama, I thought you--
等一下 媽媽 媽媽
wait, mama-- mama!
我需要錢
I need some money.
用來幹什麼
For what?
這是我的事
That's my business.
你沒資格過問
Don't you ask me no shit like that.
-我沒有錢 -不不 不要騙我 孩子
- I don't have no money-- - no, no. Don't lie to me, boy.
我是你媽媽
I'm your mama.
那個特瑞莎跟你一點關係都沒有
That bitch over there ain't no kin of you.
我才是你的親人 知道嗎
I'm your blood, remember?
我現在感覺很不好
Now I ain't feeling good.
我需要解脫
I need something to help me out.
求你了 寶貝
Come on, baby.
我去哪兒找錢啊
Where I'm supposed to get money from?
什麼
What?
特瑞莎難道沒給你點錢嗎
Teresa ain't give you nothing, huh?
她怎麼可能沒給你揣點錢
Your li'l play-play mama ain't put something in your hand?
把錢給我
Give me that damn money, chiron.
Give me the damn money! Give me the damn money!
我真的沒錢
I don't have no money!
-媽媽 求你了 -把錢給我
- Mama, come on-- - give me the damn money!
好了 好了
All right! All right!
把錢給我
Give me the damn money.
給你
Here, man.
這就對了
Yes. That is what I thought.
我對她還真是瞭解
I know that bitch like a hooker know her trick.
你是我的孩子 好嗎
You my child, okay?
告訴她最好不要忘了
And tell that bitch she better not forget it.
接著去上學
Go on to school.
你沒遲到嗎
Ain't you late?
所以現在你可以知道白血球減少
So you can see how a lack of white blood cells
對人體很危險 對不對
can be dangerous to the human body, right?
好 有人能解釋一下 如果沒有足夠的白血球
Okay, can anybody explain what will happen to the body
人體會有什麼反應嗎
if there's not enough white blood cells?
如果沒人回答問題
Ain't nobody's leaving this classroom
就不下課
until I get a response.
相信我 這個問題你知道比我知道要更重要
This is more important for you than it is for me, trust me.
嘿 小不點
Hey yo, little!
走這麼快去哪
Where you going to so fast, huh?
-我要回家 -什麼
- I'm going home. - Huh?
我跟你說了 我要回家
Man, I told you. I'm going home!
你覺得我們傻嗎 你住在那邊
You think we stupid? You live over there, nigga.
哦 不對 他要去特瑞莎家
Oh no, he going to Teresa house.
特瑞莎 那不是胡安的女朋友嗎
Teresa? That's Juan lady, ain't it?
是哦 她長得可真是漂亮呢
Oh yeah. She fine as hell.
-胡安才剛死沒多久 -就是啊
- Juan been dead a minute, though. - You right.
天哪 她免費口交嗎
Hell, she give free head?
還是她像寶拉那樣收費
Or does she charge like Paula?
寶拉現在便宜了
Hell, Paula getting cheap though.
口氣硬口活也硬
Talkin' like a rock can get your rock sucked!
你什麼意思
Nigga, what was that?!
放開我
Get off me, dawg.
我不搞同性戀
Now I ain't with that gay shit,
但是如果你敢惹我
but if you fuck with me
我能讓你的菊花欲罷不能
I'll give your ass more than you can handle.
讓你哭著找你的癮君子老母
Have you runnin' to your crackhead-ass mama.
我的天吶
My nigga!
-操你媽的 -你說什麼
- Fuck y'all niggas! - What'd you say?!
有種再說一遍 我保證不打死你
Say that shit again dog, I swear.
不敢了
Whatever, man.
那就好 你最好給我識相點
A'ight, you better stay your ass right there
別自討苦吃
if you know what's good for you.
為什麼你的牛仔褲這麼緊
Yo, why your jeans so tight?
唷 彼佐 你看這個人的牛仔褲
Yo, pizzo, you see these nigga's jeans be?
你看到了嗎
You see that shit?
黑蛋快被擠爆了吧
Nigga nuts must be chokin' in those!
-說的是實話 -好了 祝你好夢 小不點
- Real talk! - A'ight, night little.
回頭見了
See your ass later.
你是在等我嗎
You was waitin' for me?
嗯 很高興見到你
Well, nice to see you too.
你來這兒幹什麼 兄弟
What you doing out here, man?
你來這兒幹什麼
What you doing out here?
這是我抽煙的地兒 哥們
This is my smoker habitat, nigga.
怎麼 你也出來抽煙
Oh what, you smoke out here too?
差不多吧
Something like that...
你不吸煙
Nah, you don't smoke.
裝啥
Why you pretending?
在我面前裝蒜嗎 小黑
Trying to put on a show for me, black?
你為什麼總是這麼叫我
Why you always calling me that?
-什麼 小黑 -嗯 小黑
- What, black? - Yeah, black.
這是我給你取的昵稱 你不喜歡嗎
That's my nickname for you. You don't like it?
不是 只不過
No, it's just...
什麼人才會
...what kind of dude goes around
到處給別人取昵稱啊
giving other dudes nicknames?
就是我這種剛坐下來
The kind of dude what just sat down
來給你點上雪茄的人 兄弟
and is about to put you onto this blunt, nigga.
耶
Yeah.
你喜歡水嗎
You like the water?
我可以給你點「火」
I can introduce you to some "Fiyah."
試一下 兄弟 又不會咬你
Come on, nigga. It ain't gonna bite you.
天哪 我還不知道你抽煙是這個樣子
Damn, I didn't know you smoked like that.
我媽媽在家裏什麼都抽
My mom leaves all types of shit around.
微風讓我感覺很舒服 哥們
That breeze feel good as hell man.
確實是這樣
Yeah, it do.
有時候在我們住的街道附近
Sometimes round the way, where we live...
你都能感覺到同樣的風
...you can catch that same breeze.
穿過住宅區 好像所有的事
It just come through the hood and it's like everything stop
都暫時停下來了
for a second...
因為所有人都想感受一下
...'cause everyone just wanna feel it.
一切都變得安靜 你知道嗎
Everything just gets quiet, you know?
你唯一能聽見的就是自己的心跳
And it's like all you can hear is your own heartbeat.
是嗎
Right?
對
Yeah...
感覺真的很好 兄弟
Feel so good, man.
真的很好
So good...
見鬼 讓人想哭
Hell, shit make you wanna cry, feel so good.
你哭了
You cry?
沒有
Nah.
只是想哭
Makes me want to.
你為什麼哭
What you cry about?
有時候我會哭個不停
Shit, I cry so much sometimes
感覺自己都快變成水做的了
I feel like I'm gon' just turn into drops.
感覺自己可以一頭扎進水裏 是嗎
Think you can roll out into the water, right?
扎進水裏 就像所有人都想
Roll out into the water like all these other motherfuckers
把麻煩事都拋在腦後
around here trying to drown they sorrows.
你為什麼這麼說
Why you say that?
我聽出你是這個意思 兄弟
I'm just listening to you, nigga.
聽起來像是你想要做的事
Sound like something you wanna do.
我想做很多講不通的事
I wanna do a lot of things that don't make sense.
我沒有說講不通啊
I didn't say it don't make sense.
但是和我說說 有什麼事
But tell me, like-like what?
是你覺得講不通的
Like what "Lot of things"?
天哪
Damn dog...
你個八婆
...you nosey.
奇倫現在也會罵人了
Chiron cursing now, huh?
-你和我鬧呢 -隨便你怎麼說 哥們
You trying to get smart with me? - Whatever, man.
你和我耍小聰明呢 奇倫
Nah, you trying to get smart with me, huh chiron?
你和我耍小聰明呢
Yeah, you trying to get smart with me, huh.
抱歉
I'm sorry...
抱什麼歉
What you gotta be sorry for?
你之前沒做過這樣的事吧
You ain't never done nothing like that before, huh?
謝謝你載我回來 哥們
Thanks for the ride, man.
不客氣 小黑
No problem, black.
回見
I'll see you around.
好
Yeah...
回見
...see you around.
過來 寶貝
Come here, baby.
過來
Come here.
你不再愛我了
You don't love me no more...
你不再愛我了啊
你是我的唯一
You're my only.
我也是你的唯一
I'm your only.
你是我的唯一
You're my only...
-你好啊 凱文 -特雷爾 別來無恙
- Yo, what's up, kev? - Terrell, what's up man?
嘿 上學真沒意思
Hey, you know a nigga don't see school no more.
是啊 你說得對
No, I hear you, man.
以前的午餐太難吃了
Lunch used to be the shit, though.
吶 食物本來就沒好過
Nah, the food wasn't never good.
老兄 我沒在說食物
Man, I ain't talkin' 'bout the food.
但是週五的披薩真是爛到爆
But that Friday pizza was the shit.
是啊 我懂你
Yeah, I feel you.
但你還是否記得在中學的時候
Nah, but you remember in middle school,
我們玩的遊戲
that game we used to play?
「一拳打倒/躺在地下」
"Knock down/stay down"?
是喲 我是玩那個遊戲的一把好手
Yeah yo, my crazy ass was the king of that shit.
是 我記得
Yeah I remember. Yo!
你記得被你虐翻了的那個白人小孩麼
You remember that white kid you fucked up?
古巴佬是麼 馬裏西奧還是什麼
Cuban cat, right? Mauricio or something?
對 你簡直把他虐慘了
Oh yeah! Yo, you fucked that kid's face up!
從此以後我們可都叫你泰森
We was calling you Tyson after that shit.
是啊
Yeah.
但是 啊
Yo, but, uh...
現在大家都不這麼玩了
...niggas don't do that shit no more.
有點可惜
I mean... you know...
你想說什麼
What you sayin'?
我說的是 如果我選中一個人
I'm sayin' is, if I point a nigga out...
你會把他打趴下嗎
...is you gonna knock his ass down?
這就是遊戲規則呀
That's the game, ain't it?
你問我敢不敢打人 如果我打了責任就在你
You dare me to swing on him and if I do, it's on you.
好啊 好啊 凱文
A'ight. A'ight kev.
來看看誰今天要被打趴下咯
Let me see who ass gettin' dropped today.
別再喝這個黏糊糊的果汁了
Don't be drinking none of this gummy juice.
它會要了你的命
Shit'll kill you.
喲 凱文
Yo, kev.
打他
Hit that nigga.
打他 凱文
Hit that nigga, kev.
嘿 打那個基佬
Yeah, hit his faggot ass!
你等啥呢 快上
The fuck you waitin' on? Do it! Come on.
來吧
Let's go.
你感覺如何 奇倫
How you like that, chiron?
喲 我覺得他還想來一下
Yo, I think he want another.
再給他一下 快
Another one. Do it.
給他一拳
Give it to him.
你最好別起來
Don't you get up, bruh.
躺下
You stay down!
如果他起來 再把他打倒
Yeah if he get back up, knock his faggot ass back down.
-奇倫 躺下 -他起來了
- Chiron, stay down! - He got up.
求你了老兄
Come on, man.
躺下
Stay down.
再來一拳
Do it again.
打他 打他
Do it! Do it!
聽著 小伙
Listen, son...
如果你不起訴他們
If you don't press charges...
我就無法防止這些事再次發生
...I can't stop this from happening.
明白嗎
Understand?
你不知道
You don't even know.
-哦 我不懂嗎 -不懂
- Oh I don't? - Nu-uh.
你認為這是最近才有的嗎 小孩兒
You think all this just started, boy?
-我不是小孩兒 -你當然不是
- I ain't no boy. - The hell you ain't.
如果你是個成年男人
If you were a man
你旁邊就應該坐著其他四個蠢貨了
there'd be four other knuckleheads sittin' right next to you.
你一點都不明白
You don't even know.
聽著 小伙子 聽著
Listen, son, listen.
聽我說
Listen.
我不怪你
I'm not blaming you... I'm not.
我知道這很難
I know it's hard.
相信我
Believe me.
我不是不尊重你的勇敢
I'm not trying to disrespect your struggle.
我只是想讓你知道
I just need you to know...
好吧 集中注意力
All right, all right. Stay focused.
嘿 奇倫
Hey-- hey, chiron!
放開我
Get the fuck off me, niggas!
Get the fuck off me!
不要看著我
Don't look at me!
-你好 哥們 -喲 最近怎麼樣 老兄
- Hello, homie? - Yo, what's good with you, b?
看上誰了
vibing, vibing?
-什麼 -你是不是看上誰了
- What's that? - You vibin'?
-我正在盡力 -盡力
- I'm trying to. - Trying to?
那你的馬子呢
So where the hos at?
老兄 你微笑的樣子
Nigga, you smiling and shit
裝的跟不知道我在說啥一樣
like you don't know what the fuck I'm talking about.
你馬子呢 老兄
Where the hos at, nigga?
我不知道 你說呢
I don't know. You tell me.
那個街角住著一個漂亮姑娘
There's this bitch that stay down the corner.
名字叫啥
What's her name?
-阿佛羅德西亞 -你編的吧
- Afrodesia. - You making that up.
我不信你
I don't believe you.
我從沒見過你和哪個女的在一起 我不信你
I ain't never seen you with no bitch, I don't believe you.
-她的名字阿佛羅德西亞 -她在哪
- Her name afrodesia. - Her name afrodesia? Where she at?
-她只在夜間出沒 -好吧
- She only come out at night. - Okay.
-是啊 -嗯
- Yeah. - Okay.
錢少了 特拉維斯
You short, Travis.
-等等 什麼 -剩下那部分錢呢
- Wait, what? - Where the rest of the roll?
都在這了
It's all there.
你也許覺得我磕嗨了
I mean you might think I tripping,
我給你的時候一定是齊的
when I handed it to you it was all there.
沒事
It's a'ight.
如果都在這了 那你數數吧 特拉維斯
If it's all there then count that shit then, trav.
如果都在這兒 數數吧
Count it. If it's all there.
讓開 你擋著我了
Move, you're in my spot.
讓開
Move.
把我的錢拿過來
Give me my fucking money.
你是說我騙你咯
You sayin' I'm a liar?
好吧
All right.
我並沒這麼說
I ain't say that.
我告訴你數數少了多少 你說沒少
I told you to count what's off and you said it wasn't.
那你就是在說我在說謊咯
That's you calling me a liar.
我只是告訴你
Nah, all I did was tell you that--
你說什麼
you-you did what?
我他媽跟你開玩笑的
I'm just fucking with you.
數得沒錯
Count good.
做得也沒錯
Did real good.
給
Here.
做這一行 如果忍受不了別人耍你
Can't be on the corner if you can't take a nigga
你很難立足的 懂我吧
just fuckin' with you, you feel me?
嗯
Yeah.
奇倫 媽媽來電話啦
Chiron, this your mama.
我知道很晚了
I know it's late but...
但我猜你從不早睡
...I figured you ain't never been one much for sleep.
亞特蘭大沒那麼大吧
Atlanta ain't but so big...
我還是希望 你能時不時回來看看媽媽
...seemin' me you come see your mama from time to time.
做個好夢 寶貝
Hope you gettin' some rest, baby.
希望不久後你能回來
Hope you come by soon.
媽 已經太晚了
Ma, it's late.
我明天就去看你 我保證
I'll be there tomorrow, I promise.
嘿
Hello?
嘿 小黑
Hey black,
嗯 我是說 奇倫
I mean... chiron.
你好 老兄 我是凱文
What's up, man. This... this Kevin.
你在嗎
You there?
嗯
Yeah...
很久不見了 對吧
Long time, no see, right?
老兄 我跟特瑞莎要了你的電話
Man, I had to ask Teresa for your number, and...
等等 老兄 你還記得我吧
Hold on, man. You do-you do remember me, right?
是啊 我記得
Yeah, I do.
真是過去好久了
Been a while.
是啊是啊 老兄
Yeah. Yeah, it has, man.
所以 嗯 你現在在哪
So, uh, where you at now, man?
佐治亞
Georgia.
亞特蘭大
Atlanta.
我從那之後就一直在這裏了
I've been up here ever since...
嗯 嗯 我聽說了
Yeah. Yeah, man, that's what I heard.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 老兄 我對之前發生的事情很抱歉
Hey, man, I'm sorry about all that...
那些不應該發生的破事 抱歉
All that... Shit what went down... chiron.
我是混蛋 真的
Real shit, dawg, I am.
所以
So, uh...
你現在在做什麼
...what you doin' up there, man?
沒啥 都是
Not much. Just...
麻煩事
...just trouble.
奇倫總愛惹麻煩啊
Chiron and trouble always found a way.
是啊 差不多吧
Yeah... something like that.
你呢
What about you?
我
Me?
我是個廚子
I'm a cook, man.
你 你當廚子了
Y-y-you a cook?
是啊
Yeah, buddy.
我之前被派去做一些愚蠢的活計
Man, I got sent up for some stupid shit-
就像之前一樣
the same stupid shit we always get sent up for.
他們把我分配到廚房
They put me on the kitchen line, man,
我覺得還不錯
and I kinda took to it.
不管怎麼說 我只
Anyway, man, I just--
我只是很想你
I just thought about you, man. I...
這裏有個點唱機
We got this jukebox in here and, uh...
有人點歌 它就會播放
...and folks come by and play they songs,
點唱機裏的唱片
that's the music we get in here...
有一首歌
This dude, man...
讓我想起了你
...just reminded me of you.
所以
So, uh...
嘿 如果你什麼時候來城裏 記得來和我打招呼
Hey man, if you ever come to town, man, you come holla at me.
我可以給你做點什麼吃
I'll cook you somethin'.
也許
Maybe...
也許可以給你點那首歌
Maybe play that song for you.
好啦 老兄 好好睡吧
All right man, um... You be easy, all right?
你最近怎麼樣
How you been?
我很好啊
I'm all right.
還是睡不著
I ain't sleepin'.
為什麼呢
Why not?
-嗯 如果你知道 -做惡夢
- Right. If you knew you'd... - Bad dreamin'.
還是嗎
Still?
你都沒嘗試過跟誰說說
You ever thought about talking about it with somebody?
甚至不需要是一個心理顧問
Maybe not even a counsellor.
也許可以跟你媽媽說說
Maybe somebody like your mama?
嗯
Yeah...
嗯 我也覺得這麼說挺好笑的
Yeah, it sound funny to me too.
你和特瑞莎聊過了嗎
You talk to Teresa?
嗯
Yeah.
她怎麼樣
How she doing?
很好
Good.
「很好」
"Good."
媽 你打算什麼時候回家
When you go home, ma?
家
Home?
這裏就是家 你知道
This is home. You know...
我是說 他們願意留下我工作
I mean, they allowing me to stay and work
多久都行 我覺得
as long as I like. I figure...
能幫幫別人也是好事
...might as well help other folks.
讓我不惹麻煩
Keep myself out of trouble.
挺好的 媽
That's good, mama.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊 我也這麼想
Yeah, I think it is too.
真的
I really do.
你還在街上做生意嗎
So, you still in them streets?
你大老遠跑去佐治亞
Didn't come all the way the hell to Georgia
卻干了同樣齷齪的勾當
to have you fallin' in the same shit,
-奇倫 -我要走了 要走了
-chiron. - Im'ma go. Im'ma go--
不 不不不 你聽著
no, no, no, no, you gon' listen!
聽你的嗎 媽媽
To who, ma? Huh?
聽你的嗎
To you?
真的假的
Really, though?
拜託
Please...
我是個廢物
I messed up.
我曾經毀滅了生活中的一切
I fucked it all the way up.
我知道
I know that.
但是你不要走我的老路啊 寶貝
But yo' heart ain't gotta be black like mine, baby.
我愛你 奇倫
I love you, chiron.
真的
I do.
我愛你 寶貝
I love you, baby.
但是你不愛我也沒關係
But you ain't gotta love me.
上帝知道我沒有在你需要的時候給你我的愛
Lord knows I did not have love for you when you needed it,
我知道
I know that.
所以你不愛我沒關係
So you ain't gotta love me...
但你要知道我愛你
...but you gon' know that I love you.
聽到了
You hear?
你聽見了嗎 奇倫
You hear me, chiron?
聽見了 媽媽
I hear you, mama.
我來
Here.
我很抱歉 寶貝
I'm sorry, baby.
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
過來 媽媽
Come here, mama.
請稍等
Be right with you.
兩位吃的好嗎
How y'all doin'?
好嗎 那很好
Good? All right.
我把這些收拾了
I'll take these.
一會回來把賬單給您
I'll be right back with your check.
一會兒來招待您
Be right with you, boss,
讓我收拾一下
just let me get this out the way.
好了
All right...
好了先生 您要點什麼
All right, man, how you doing tonight?
我能為您
What can I get you--
奇倫
chiron?
天 老兄 你怎麼不說話
Damn man, why you ain't say nothin'?
你好嗎 凱文
'Sup, kev?
哎呀 老兄
Damn, man,what--
你在這裏做什麼
what you doing down here?
我是說
I mean--
嘿
hey, hey...
你來了 這是最重要的事情
You here now, man, that's all that matter.
又來了 只會點頭啊 老夥計
There go that damn noddin' again, man,
你真是一點都沒變
you ain't-you ain't changed one damn bit.
你現在還是不能一次說三個字以上嗎
You still can't say more than three words at a time, huh?
你說過要為我做點吃的
Said you was gon' cook for me,
這我還是會說的
I know how to say that.
是啊 我的確說過 對吧
Yeah, I did say that, didn't I?
看你這身材可不缺吃的
Don't look like your ass been missing no meals.
是啊
Yeah.
沒事 我來弄點吃的 你坐吧
But I got you, man. Sit down.
坐下 老兄 你想要點啥
Sit down, man. What you want?
你可以點菜單上的
You can order off the menu if you want to, or...
或者來試試我的主廚特色菜
Hey... I could just hit you with that chef's special.
嗯
Yeah.
沒問題 凱龍
We here, chiron.
一份主廚特色菜 馬上就來
One chef's special... Coming right up.
主廚特色菜來了
Chef's special.
哦 所以你現在是古巴主廚咯
Oh, so you Cuban now?
只是在廚藝風格上而已
Only in the kitchen, papi.
坐下吧
Yo, sit down, man.
或者你想站著吃
Or are you gon' eat standin' up?
想喝點什麼嗎
You want a drink?
不了 我不喝
Nah, I don't drink.
真是十年沒見的樣子
Nigga I ain't seen you in like a decade,
你必須跟我喝兩杯
you gon' drink with me.
夠了夠了 你在幹嘛
Nah, bruh, nah! What you doing, man?
歡迎回來 老兄
Welcome back, bruh.
我還以為你說你不喝呢
Damn, bother, I thought you said you didn't drink...
嘗不出酒的味道 不敢多喝
Can't really taste it so I don't mess with it.
-我看見了 我看見了 -什麼啊
- I saw that. I saw that. - What? What?
你一點都不想浪費 特別好吃吧
You don't wanna waste none of that, do you? It tastes good.
得了吧 老哥 還不錯吧
Chill out, man. It's straight.
-說什麼 -還不錯
- Say what? - It's straight.
還不錯
It's straight.
兄弟 怎麼也比盒飯好吃吧
Man, please, it's better than chef boyardee, ain't it?
得了吧
Chill out, bruh.
我煮的意面都是硬的
My spaghetti-o's go hard, man.
嘿 慢慢吃
Hey, eat your dinner, man.
慢慢吃
Eat your dinner.
再喝點嗎 喬治先生
Got it, Mr. George?
我馬上回來
I'll be back.
嘿兄弟 你記得薩蔓莎嗎
Hey man, you... You remember Samantha?
漂亮的薩蔓莎
Fine-ass Samantha.
是 我記得她
Yeah, I remember her.
嗯
Yeah?
看看
Check this out.
小凱文
Kevin Jr.
我和薩蔓莎的兒子
Me and Samantha, man.
我們很早就有了他
We had him young, too young.
老兄 進監獄之後生活太艱難
Man, when I got locked up, man, that shit was hard.
我再也回不去原來的街區了
Wasn't no way I could go back the streets, man.
回不去了
Not after this.
-你們還在一起嗎 -我和薩蔓莎嗎
- Y'all still down? - Me and Sam?
沒有 我的意思是
Nah. I mean...
我們挺好的
...we cool.
你知道的 因為小孩子我們不得不這樣 但
We gotta be, you know, 'cause of li'l man, but...
只不過不是從前那樣了
...nah, not like that, man.
你呢 兄弟
What about you, bruh?
我嗎
What about me?
跟我說說吧
Nigga... tell me somethin'.
你在做什麼
I mean, what you doin'?
和誰在一起
Who you doin'?
說吧
Man, come on now.
我在廚房忙前忙後
I've been back there in that kitchen, man,
給你做菜
and cooked for your ass and everything, man, hey,
吃人家的嘴軟
these grandma rules, man.
拿人家的手短
You know the deal.
吃飽喝足了 該說說了
Your ass eat, your ass speak.
好吧 那我就直說了
All right, straight up?
說吧 直接說
Yeah, nigga, straight up.
我在販毒
I'm trappin'.
什麼
What?
嗯
Yeah.
因為打了那個男孩
When they sent me to Atlanta,
他們送我到亞特蘭大的少管所
put me straight into juvie for beatin' the old boy.
在那裏我遇到一個人
Met this dude in there.
我出來以後 他讓我上街賣毒品
When I come out, he put me on the block.
後來我混得風生水起
Did good at it and rose up.
就是這樣
It is what it is.
胡說
Bullshit, man.
不應如此
That ain't what it is.
那不是你 奇倫
That ain't you, chiron.
你又不瞭解我
Nigga, you don't know me.
我不瞭解你嗎
I don't know you?
這是您的小票
There you are.
二十四點五美元
$24.50.
你為什麼要戴金牙
Why you got them damn fronts, man?
為什麼給我打電話
Why'd you call me?
什麼
What?
我問你為什麼打電話給我
Why did you call me?
我告訴過你的
I told you, man...
-有個男人走進來 -說重點
...dude came in... - Yeah, yeah, yeah...
他放了首歌
He played this song, man...
這是你的車嗎
This you?
你說販毒還真不是開玩笑說說的啊
You wasn't playin' 'bout them traps, huh.
開始飆車了嗎
Ride dirty, huh?
差不多吧
Something like that.
你怎麼上下班
So how you be in to work?
坐公交
Bus.
黑車
Jitney.
有時當我帶著小凱文的時候
Sometimes Samantha shoot me out there
薩曼塔會來接我
when I got li'l kev.
在邁阿密沒車的日子簡直無法想像
I can't picture bein' in Miami with no car.
-這倒是真的 -我想也是
- Man, it's real out here. - Yeah, I bet.
這裏天氣又熱 車又慢 還特別堵
Real hot, real slow, and real busted.
感覺自己像個窩囊廢
Shot me like a duck out here, man.
你說什麼
This nigga said "A duck."
-你喝高了吧 -你知道我在做什麼
- Yeah, you on one. - You know what I'm doin'.
我就是有點累了
Nah, I'm just tired, bruh.
謝謝你載我
Hey man, bet on the ride, though.
-沒事 -很感激你
- Yeah. - Appreciate it.
不用客氣
Yeah, man.
總不能讓你坐黑車吧
Can't have yo ass on no jitney.
奇倫
So chiron...
你那樣看著我幹嘛
What-what you looking at me like that for?
兄弟 告訴我 你為什麼突然開車過來
What man, come on, you just drove down here?
嗯
Yeah.
還是說你嗑嗨了
Like you was just- you was just on one...
就開上高速路嗎
...and you hit the highway?
是的
Yeah.
那你今晚在哪裏過夜
So where you got' stay tonight, man?
當心 我看著你的
Watch that shit. - I got you.
就是這裏了
This the spot.
進來吧 就當是自己家一樣
Come on in. Get yourself at home.
-挺不錯 -等我一下 我去換衣服
- This is real, man. - I'm just... get out of this real quick.
你還好嗎
You a'ight?
還好 就是有點頭疼
Yeah, no, I just got a little headache.
你還真是不勝酒力
Man, you a lightweight.
是你倒的酒
Nah, you was pouring that mug. You was pouring it.
-我嘗不出味道 -別說了
- "I can't taste this". - Chill out, man.
-我們喝了得有三瓶吧 -對 三瓶
- We had like three bottles. - Yeah, three bottles.
我給你沏點綠茶吧
I'll make you some green tea, man, come on.
我才不喝那種東西
I won't be drinking that shit either, man.
-那你要喝什麼 -水
- What do you drink? - Water.
你是誰
Who is you, man?
誰 我嗎
Who, me?
對 你
Yeah, nigga. You.
我是說 你的金牙
I'm saying, man, them fronts.
那輛車
That car.
你到底是誰 奇倫
Who is you, chiron?
我在做自己
I'm me, man.
我沒有要做別人啊
I ain't tryin' to be nothin' else.
好吧 那你現在很厲害啊
Oh, okay. So you hard now?
-我沒那麼說 -那是怎樣
- I ain't say that. - Well then what?
嘿 我不是在說你不好 只是
Hey, hey, hey, I ain't tryin' to hem you up, man, it's just...
有太久沒見你了
I ain't seen you in a minute and...
你與我想像中不太一樣
...it's not what I expected.
那你想像的是怎樣的我
Well what did you expect?
你還記得
You remember...
上一次我見到你的時候嗎
You remember the last time I saw you?
太久了 我盡量不去想
For a long time, tried not to remember.
試著忘掉過去的種種
Tried to forget all those times.
好吧
Yeah.
我來到亞特蘭大
When we got to Atlanta...
開始了新的生活
...I started over.
白手起家
Built myself from the ground up.
變得強大起來
Built myself hard.
-你怎麼樣 -我嗎
- What about you? You-- - me?
我根本不值一提
I wasn't never really worth shit.
只是渾渾噩噩地活著
Just kept on, man.
從未實現過心中所想
Never really did anything I actually wanted to do.
我能做的
It was all I could do was
就是活成別人所想的樣子
to do what folks thought I should be doing.
我從來沒真正做自己
I wasn't never really myself.
現在呢
And now?
現在
Now?
如今
Now, man...
我有了小凱文
...now I got li'l kev.
做著這份工作
Got this job.
十八個月的實習期
Another 18 months of probation.
真實無比
That 's some real shit, man.
這就是我的人生
Nah, man. It's a life.
你知道嗎
You know?
我從來沒經歷過這樣的生活
I ain't never had that before.
現在的我
Like...
疲於奔命
Like, I'm tired as hell right now, man,
掙著這點小錢
and I ain't making more than shoe money, but...
但是我已經不再煩惱了
...I ain't got no worries, man.
我是說以前的種種煩惱
Not them kind what I had before.
這是真實的生活
That's that real shit.
就像鮑勃·馬利說過的那樣
That's that Bob Marley shit, nigga.
這一生只有你撫摸過我
You the only man that's ever touched me.
只有你一個
You're the only one.
從那以後我也沒再碰過別人
I haven't really touched anyone, since.